♪ [music] ♪
We welcome, Ms. Joan Rivers!
[applause]
You know, you're going to be
a big star.
Here's my dappy, little friend,
Joan Rivers!
[screaming]
[applause]
[announcer] Joan Rivers,
the groundbreaking female comedian
paves the way for women everywhere.
[Joan Rivers] You know, I know who is gay
and who's not gay--can we talk to you?
[applause]
[male presenter] The Grammy goes to...
[female presenter] Joan Rivers!
[applause]
[announcer] Here's Joan Rivers!
Please don't, I'm very, very late.
♪ [music] ♪
[announcer] I hope you had a few drinks
'cause you're gonna need them.
Will you welcome please,Ms. Joan Rivers!
[applause]
This is my career.
I mean, how depressing is this?
[laughter]
Forty years in the fucking business
and this is where you end up.
[audience laughter]
Just to show you...
My daughter and I are very close,
very, very close.
But I brought her up all wrong.
I brought her up to have morals.
She turned down doing
Playboy magazine cover,
how about that?
Four hundred thousand dollars,
naked to the waist.
Turned it fuckin' down
and calls me up for approval.
For approval!
"Mother, I turned down Playboy.
What do you think?"
And you know--what do I think?
I'm very proud of you, Melissa.
What do I think?
What do I think,
you stupid, fucking cunt!
What do I think?
[audience laughter]
I think you should ask 200,000 more
and show your pussy! That's what I think!
[audience applause and laughter]
I'm a 75 year-old woman up here
playing dumps in Queens!
What do I think?
[audience laughter]
I'm on a fucking red carpet
in the hot sun
talking to these assholes,
"Where are you from?"
"Got a lucky charm."
"Who the fuck are you?"
[audience applause and laughter]
♪ [music] ♪
[Joan] Not good. This is not good.
We have no Vegas, no giant club dates.
Kathy Griffin's taken all those away.
I have the play, which is
not going to give me any money.
Can we get club dates?
Can't Billy get club dates?
And this is not a full book.
Like a little date here and there.
Yeah.
- Sure.
[Joan] These were the good years.
[Personal assistant] These were
the good years.
See this is the kind of a book I like.
Now that's a good page.
You know what I mean?
These are good pages.
Ten o'clock, eleven o'clock.
Twelve thirty, this and that.
That's happiness.
Last year was a very difficult year.
I was playing, here we go,
the Bronx at 4:30 in the afternoon.
That was a real good one.
I'll show you fear.
That's fear.
If my book ever looked like this,
it would mean that nobody wants me,
That everything I ever tried to do
in life didn't work.
Nobody cared and I've been
totally forgotten.
When you say, "Joan, get out your
calendar," she says, "Hold on on
let me put my sunglasses on
because the white of the page
hurts my eyes."
So, that's a joke.
So we used to laugh about that.
"Hold on, let me get my sunglasses."
"Okay, what day?"
You look handsome.
Yeah, right.
Billy looks good and he can't
stand it.
I can't.
[female] Why not?
My career is in the toilet
That's me.
[laughs]
My career is in the toilet
nothing is going right,
That's right
- Nothing.
[female] Why?
I don't know it's like, ya know?
[Joan] That's what I always tell them.
That still gets me.
[Joan] Billy Sammeth is a big part
of my life, a huge part of my life.
He knows my history, you know
there are so few people
that you can say, do you
remember Bernie Brillstein
and we both laugh and laugh.
[Billy Sammeth]
Joan is a chronic workaholic.
One job a day is not enough
it's almost like an addict.
Sadly, but she's a work addict
so it's not enough, no matter
how much you give her
it doesn't fill up that need to
be working.
Now this is Jocelyn Pickett,
this is my assistant
who is now going to show you busy I am.
Anybody call?
[together] No.
[Larry Thompson] It's not about
whether the talent is good,
it's about whether they're hot.
There are times in people's careers
that you just can't get it going.
Careers do that, you're hot, you're not,
you're in a slump, you're not.
Nothing is happening right now,
so she needs some heat.
[female] Steve LaVean's office.
Jennifer Mowen?
Hi, Billy Sabbath.
And Joan Rivers.
Hi, Joan Rivers, hold on just a moment.
Hello.
I'd get through faster
if I was Kathy Griffin.
[male voice] Hello.
Hi.
[Billy] I see her about Harrah's,
which is May 18th,
which is the weekend before Memorial Day.
I just think it's wrong. It's not
vacation, the kids are still in school.
I want a letter from them saying, we
acknowledge the worst weekend,
one of the worst weekends of the year.
[male voice] Okay.
[Joan] And I really don't need
at this age, where I'm a comedy icon,
I don't need to walk into a room
and have it half full
and then have the Harrah's people go
cluck, cluck, cluck.
[Billy] Right now they see her
as a plastic surgery freak,
who's past due her, you know,
her, "Sell by date," was finished.
But God help the next Queen of Comedy
because this one is not abdicating.
Never will.
There'll be nail marks on that red carpet
before she abdicates.
So good luck to the next Queen.
♪ [together] Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday to you ♪
Age, it's the one mountain
that you can't overcome.
It's a youth society and nobody wants you.
"Your too old, you're too old,
you're too old."
If one more woman comedian comes up
and says to me,
"You opened the doors for me," and you
want to say,
"Go fuck yourself,
I'm still opening the doors."
[host] You are a Barnard College graduate?
- Yeah.
[host] And your father's a doctor?
- Yes.
[host] You live, where? In Scarsdale?
In Larchmont.
[host] In Larchmont.
And your mother is a...?
A mother.
[TV host] ...just a mother.
[audience laughs].
How do they look upon this,
what you're doing, what it is you do?
Frightened.
[TV host] Are they?
- A lot.
Well, now they are very show biz.
And my mother and I are thinking of doing
a sister act. But um...
[audience laughs].
The audience here really liked you
and good luck to you.
[audience clapping].
It's been very nice, thank you.
[Jocelyn] Joan, here is a script
for the TV pilot you wanted to look at.
Ok, thank you. Do you know where
I am in this?
[phone ringing].
I see no Joan on page 2,
I see no Joan on page 3.
I see no Joan on page 4.
I have worked with her for about 15 years,
I think, somewhere in there,
so I definitely have gone through kind
of the ups and downs,
you know with her, with her career.
When I started it was definitely kind of a
lower point,
Her daytime talk show was cancelled,
at the same time her play,
"Sally Marr," which ran on Broad Way,
that shut down.
Everything was kind of closing, you know,
at that point.
So of course Joan, being Joan,
then started to try and reinvent herself.
No, I ain't seeing me.
This year is no different.
Joan is looking at new projects,
new ways to get out there.
And she's got two new books coming out.
A new play that she's really worked on
very hard for the past couple of years.
And, "Celebrity Apprentice."
She's booked to be on the next series
of, "Celebrity Apprentice."
So she's hoping one of them hits
and puts her back on top.
I can't find me anywhere.
♪ [music] ♪
What we are planning is
the cut-off date of the...
the Tony Nominations
is somewhere in April,
so we have to open
somewhere in April.
The next few months,
I am really focusing just on my play.
It means a great deal to me
because it tells my life story.
So she calls me up one day and she goes,
"Billy, its Joan, listen,
I wrote a script a couple of years ago,
it's in the drawer."
Now, I actually saw a reading of it
a year earlier and I enjoyed it.
So I said, "I think you should do it."
Hi Joanie.
Hi, Billy boy.
[muah, muah]
Hi, Billy.
This is Billy.
Hello, Sandra.
Hello, Schmidtzy, how you doing?
Schmidt Schmidt, Schmidt.
[together] Schmidtzy.
[Sean Foley] The name of the show is,
"Joan Rivers - A Work in Progress
by A Life in Progress."
You know, episodes from her life.
How she got to where she is now.
We're going to take this to the
Edinburgh Festival,
and then we're going to do it
in London's Glittering West End.
The ultimate goal, I think Joan wants
to play it in her home town.
I have very few hairs left on my head
and each one has a name.
They--"Last week we had the
Sit Shiva for Bernice."
"And we buried Bernice." Or,
"We cremated Bernice."
Yeah, "Cremated," I think is good.
"...last week."
I hope that the play is a huge success.
I think the play will remind them,
I'm an actress, I'm a writer
and if we get great reviews,
it will open up a million other things.
One of my earliest
memories, I must have been
tops 6 years old, my mother took me
to see Paul Robeson in Othello
and I remember smelling the smells
of the theater and I thought,
this is where I belong.
I was in every school play. I was in
everything you could do at college.
There was never a discussion
in my own head of where I was going.
And I was always acting, always going to
be an actress.
[female] Were you were straight acting
or comedy, or...?
[Joan] No, no comedy never.
I just knew that I could work the
comedian at night
and make money making rounds as an
actress.
And that's the only reason
I went into comedy.
Sometimes I sit at home
and I think to myself,
"Joan, yes, you're a diva, you're a diva.
Penthouse, limos, furs, woof, woof...
But a diva can get lonely. And I say this
to my staff. I say, "Staff..."
[laughter]
I don't learn their names
because they are like you people,
they come, they go.
Sometimes, I say to them,
"Staff, I'm lonely.
Who's going to fuck me tonight?"
[laughter]
[dog barking]
Yes, yes, yes, this is delicious, huh?
This is Kevin who runs my house also,
without asking me anything.
Thank God. That is Debbie,
his wife, over there
who is really
the brains behind Kevin.
I just thought you should know.[laughs].
That's true.
It's bacon, you idiot.
This is my apartment and it's very grand.
This is how Marie Antoinette would
have lived if she had had money.
♪ [music] ♪
You try to explain to people
before you go to her house,
what you're about to see,
nobody lives like this,
maybe the Queen of England,
but besides that, nobody lives like this.
I live very, very, very well.
That's to start with.
I enjoy my creature comforts and
I know I have to work for it.
I could stop and live carefully,
but that's ridiculous,
I don't want to live carefully.
So I would rather work and live the way
I live and have a wonderful time.
When I hear the numbers
from her accountant,
because you know, behind our client's
back, everyone is whispering,
so they call me and they say,
"Billy, you got a pull another rabbit
out of the hat."
"How many rabbits would
you like out of the hat?
"I don't have that many more
rabbits in my hat."
When I first hit on The Carson Show
years ago, my manager,
that was a man named Jack Rollins,
and he said
you're going to be an industry.
When people hit,
they become industries
and that's really it,
I'm a small industry.
I have a few checks for you to sign.
Oh, good, okay.
I've an agent, I've a manager,
I've a business manager, a PR lady,
two assistants and a lawyer.
Don't forget the lawyers.
There are then certain relatives
that I'm totally supporting,
certain friends.
Most people that work with me,
if they have children,
I send the children to private schools.
It goes on, on, on, on and on.
I'm dancing as fast as I can.
[laughs]
Are you on speaker?
[Billy] I'm here.
So where do we start?
Joannie, they want to do
a cruise with you
for $125,000 for 3 days,
where you can tie it in
and sell your jewelry.
[Billy] Should I sign it?
Yes, I would love to
because I'm very short on money.
Trust me, we need it.
[Billy] Okay.
Okay.
[Jocelyn] How about bump up the offer
and you'll do your comedy.
Yeah, bump up the offer
and they get Joan on stage.
[Billy] I will see.
Bump up the offer some more
and they get Joan doing a survival lecture
and on stage.
- [Jocelyn] Uh-hm.
Bump up the offer some more
and they also get the red carpet lecture,
the survival lecture.
[Jocelyn] And don't forget just the
125 grand worth of charm.
[laughs]
♪ [music] ♪
You know the dates we're holding the QVC,
right Billy, pretty much?
[Billy] Yeah.
Let me ask you one last thing,
do you think it's in bad taste
to say about Obama's wife,
who I think is so chic, Michelle,
that she is, remember the old days,
in the Kennedy Era,
there was the Jackie O?
Well, now in the Obama Era,
it's going to be Blackie O.
[Jocelyn] Oh, no.
- [male] What? Oh, don't.
Okay, just thought it was a great joke.
These are all my jokes.
These are jokes over the last 30 years.
These are just...
Every time I write a joke,
I try to remember to get it on a card.
"Why should a woman cook?"
"So her husband can say, 'My wife
makes a delicious cake to some hooker.'"
[laughs]
And you wonder why
I'm still working at this age.
People think it comes so easily,
they have no idea that what you're doing
is a terrifically difficult thing to do
and I prepare like a crazy lady.
And here I am, I mean,
everything is just--
everywhere you look,
there are jokes.
Jokes to be filed, jokes to be written,
jokes that I thought of something.
I mean my life is just jokes.
...Vagina farts are so loud,
"My vagina farts are so loud,
my gynecologist wears ear plugs."
[laughs]
"Are gay men proud
of their excessive body hair,
like Madonna's daughter," maybe.
"Amazing race?"
"Mel Gibson chasing Jews
into the showers."
[laughs]
As some of you can tell now,
I'm 7 1/2 months pregnant
and you want to know the
truth?
You know how lousy I feel at night
when I'm undressed
and my husband looks at me
and mentally dresses me.
[audience laughing]
When I started comedy,
I was very wild for the time
but different times.
The last line of my original act was,
"This business it's all about
casting characters,
so I just want you to know my name is
Joan Rivers and I put out."
And you would hear the audience,
such a sweet little silly line
from a girl who is 28 years old,
you know,dressed up trying to look nice.
The audience, half of them laughed,
Jack Lemon saw me and walked out.
He said, "That's disgusting."
So for my time, I was very shocking.
I remember I had
a joke about abortions
when you weren't supposed to even
say the word on television.
I have a friend who just got married.
The woman is 32 years-old,
she had 14 appendectomies,
if you know what I'm telling you.
You know,back and forth to Puerto Rico,
she never stopped flying.
She walked down the aisle in white.
Every usher went --
[audience laughing]
My manager took me out and said to me,
"Joanalah, you're going into places
you shouldn't go. It's not right,
it's not right.
Women shouldn't talk about that.
I remember thinking, "You are so wrong."
"This is exactly what we should be
talking about."
My daughter loves me very, very much.
I was there when she gave birth, yuck!
In California, they bring the parents in
now to see the birth. Yuck, yuck, yuck!
In my day, having a child was better.
They knocked you out with the first pain.
They woke you up when the hair dresser
shows, you knew nothing.
It was so much better.
"Ms. Rivers, you had a girl."
Good [puffs], good, good.
[audience laughs]
Is she normal?
"Yeah."
[audience laughs]
Good.
Is she white?
"Yeah."
Good.
[audience laughing and clapping]
And the marriage continues.
[audience laughs]
I went to see her live one time.
The shit that came out of her mouth
was so shocking and so funny,
she was doing something
that no other woman was doing.
You know, I wouldn't be doing this
if it wasn't for Joan.
Much in the way that she acknowledges
that Phyllis Diller paved the way for her.
And before her was, Moms Mabley,
I get it, there is a handful of women
in modern history that have done this.
Just a handful.
I was so angry about...
Thank you. Thank you, thank you.
While we're on the subject,
let me talk to you about sex over 60,
after 60, the body drops.
[Sean] The boobs drop.
My body, yeah,
and it's not just the breasts,
vaginas drop, vaginas drop.
Six years ago, I woke up one morning
and I said,
why am I wearing a bunny slipper
and why is it gray.
[Sean] Brilliant.
[Joan] I went to the dermatologist
so please excuse the way I look.
[Sean laughs]
I got shot filled with everything.
I said, I needed some four months.
[Sean] What have you got?
She just went crazy.
Blast away.
And then she said,
"Here, go to rehearsal."
[laughs]
Okay, thank you, Pat.
My mother told me,
"Looks don't count."
She told me this a lot.
Saturday nights, in our kitchen
while I was growing up.
My mother used to look at me and say...
[audience laughing]
"Looks don't count,
now get out of my sight, you big lump."
"And my mother lied
because looks count..."
It's very scary when you see yourself
totally without any makeup, it's really--
it gives me the willies.
Who is that person?
So I get up in the morning
and the first thing
I do is I get into makeup.
Now I was never the natural beauty.
No man has ever,
ever told me I'm beautiful.
They said to me, "You look great.";
"You look this."; "You're terrific."
But no man has ever said,
"Oh, my God, you're so beautiful."
♪ [music] ♪
Yeah. Bring them right in.
Yeah.
Good.
Yeah, good.
Okay, let's do tools.
Yeah, that's great.
Yeah, good.
Don't you want
the hand more to the side?
People want to look at pretty women.
Nobody wants an old woman.
So I started with the plastic surgery,
little bits and tweaks.
And then I got very angry,
because nobody would admit it.
I really became a big advocate of it.
And so, then I became
the poster girl for it.
And then I became the joke of it.
Yeah, that's it.
Good.
[Dr. Joy Brown Show] So how did you
come up with the title?
Matt Monro told that to me...
- Yeah?
...at a party.
Yeah. You and I were having a discussion
before we went on the air today?
[Joan] Right.
I said if you don't feel good
about yourself inside
plastic surgery will not help at all,
and in fact, can make things worse
'cause then you think,
"Well, people aren't really
appreciating the real me."
Well who is the real me?
Tell me --
You are the real me.
Well, Joan, look, we want to be loved for
our sense of humor, for our soul,
for our sweetness, for our vulnerability,
for our intelligence. Yes?
I just want to be loved.
♪ [music] ♪
I met Edgar, I'd been on the Carson Show.
Edgar called and he said to Johnnie,
"Who do you know is a good writer?"
And Carson said, "There was a girl writer
on last week. You should look her up."
I met him, I married him four days later.
Was I madly in love with him?
No.
Was it a good marriage?
Yes.
I thought marriage was going to be
hugging and kissing like in the movies.
You walk hand in hand,
over the hill into the sunset.
You know what's on the other
side of that hill?
Filthy dishes, that's what.
And socks.
How was the last show last night?
Very good as a matter of fact.
Good.
Without Edgar, I could never have done it.
We worked together.
We worked on projects together
so it was a family business.
Any woman that has a child
that doesn't yell
is a fool, don't you think?
Didn't you yell?
Why not? It's your one
chance to be noticed.
When I was having my kid,
you should...
Ahhh!
[laughter]
And that was just during conception.
I was dying to be a mother,
I couldn't wait to be a mother.
And I really worked very hard
to be there for her.
Of course, I was sure she felt
very deserted as a child,
but I was -- I was there
as much as I could be
and I made sure we were a
family unit and she knew it.
Everyone was like, "Oh,
what was it like living with a legend?"
Like yeah, it was hilarious
when I was getting grounded.
Which is why I always say to people,
you don't realize
how in these very extraordinary
abnormal circumstances
what a normal world my parents created.
And that's a testament to them.
It's funny because she refers
to her career as,"The Career,"
and it dawned on me one day
that I had a sibling.
We all worked on,
"The Career," as if it was
a totally separate entity
in the room.
Melissa, what was your mom's reaction
when you told her you wanted
to go into show business?
What was it that we used to say?
Supportive, yet not encouraging.
Yeah, and still am.
...still am.
Which is a little late in the game
to be supportive and not encouraging.
Yeah, but t's such a hard business.
What I tried to do was
I tried to protect her.
This is the one business
in the world, it is total rejection.
I'm 75 and I'm still rejected.
This business you are mud your whole life.
Josie Josie, are you there?
Yes.
Have you heard from Billy?
I haven't, I have gotten no calls back.
All right, can you send him an e-mail?
I really want him there to see the play
before we go to Edinburgh.
I mean it's Edinburgh,
it's London, my God,
He's gotta see the play.
Okay, I'll e-mail him as well.
So that's my manager Billy, who I adore,
disappears all the time.
Three years ago it was very, very bad
and I almost fired him then
and then it's God,
it's you know,all this time...
I've known Billy,
it's gotta be about 35 years.
I could open the drawer here somewhere
and you'll find pictures of Billy.
Here look, young Billy. Young Joan.
That's Edgar in the background.
And Billy is always part of my life
and I want to see him now,
because we're doing the play
and I need another pair of eyes,
I need another brain.
I need his input desperately.
Welcome, welcome, welcome
to what will be Joan River's
"A Work in Progress
By A Life in Progress."
Okay, here we go.
I am thrilled to be here.
I just don't want this to be
about me, me, me, me me.
Hello.
Not yet honey.
Again, you two, back. Go back.
[audience laughter]
Beautiful.
Anyhow -- line?
[Sean] "Now where was I?"
Now where was I?
[audience laughing and clapping].
Bill Cosby, who is
a very good friend of mine
was on the Tonight Show.
And the comic that was on
with Bill, absolutely bombed
and Bill, God bless him, went over
to the director and he said,
"Listen, why don't you use Joan Rivers,
she can't be any worse
than the guy that was on tonight."
And that's how they put me on,
they put me on the next night.
And it was one of those nights.
Do you know like,
when everything goes right?
When the stars are in alignment
and the audience, we just connected.
And Carson, at the end of the act,
after nine years of working
bungalow colonies
and strip joints and working
in Greenwich Village
in clubs where you'd pass the hat
and the hat wouldn't come back.
On the air, Carson said to me,
"You're going to be a star."
And I looked behind me,
who the hell is he talking to?
And it was absolutely --
it was magical between the two of us,
absolutely magical.
Don't you think men
really like intelligence more
when it comes right down to it?
Ahh! Please, are we gonna go back to that?
Are you kidding?
Sure, I mean it's a brain, you know?
A caring person.
No man has ever put his hand
up a woman's dress
looking for a library card.
[audience laughing]
Everyone watched the Carson Show.
And when Carson said to me,
"You're going to be a star,"
my life changed.
♪ [music] ♪
[TV host] And as we say at Cape Canaveral,
she took off like a rocket.
[Billy] The Tonight Show
was a pinnacle for Joan.
And the more guest appearances she got,
either guesting with Johnny
or guest hosting for Johnny,
the bigger and stronger the career
was going and building up and up.
And then eventually they made her
the permanent guest host
of The Tonight Show
which was a big thing.
♪ [music] ♪
After 20 years on The Tonight Show,
Fox came and offered me my own show
and Edgar would be the producer.
Of course we said yes.
The first person I called
was Johnny Carson.
He slammed the phone down.
I called him again, slammed it down again
and never spoke to me again, ever.
I think he was furious, Ihe felt betrayed.
I was now a competitor.
He literally had me black listed
and to this day,
I have not been on NBC late night, ever.
As she drove off the NBC lot,
she lost her confidence.
"Oh my God, what have I done."
It was such a bad period.
The Fox show, even before we went
on the air, was just a nightmare.
Edgar did not like Ruben Murdock
and Barry Gillette.
And from the day we walked in,
there were fights about everything.
About whether we should have a
Coke machine or a Pepsi machine,
M&Ms or Hershey Kisses.
Finally, they called me
in on a Thursday night
and they said
you've got to fire Edgar.
I couldn't do it. I couldn't, ah...
I couldn't-couldn't do it. Couldn't do it.
[TV announcer] The woman who asked,
"Can we talk?"
Joan Rivers is apparently through
as permanent host
of her late night talk show.
From there, Edgar imploded,
absolutely imploded.
He didn't have Joan's strength,
he didn't have it.
I had a call from Gavin DeBecker,
who was his security company.
he said, "Terrible news. "Yes?"
"Edgar killed himself in Philadelphia."
He left us high and dry.
Everything went to smithereens.
And he left me with no career
and a lot of debts
because he wasn't a good
businessman and a lot of tough times.
I walk past Edgar's pictures, I feel such
sadness, such darkness.
First off, Mother,
I'm very, very angry at you.
Since Daddy died, you have not spent
one minute at home.
Melissa and I, we started
immediately going into therapy,
separately and together.
And then we did something,
which sounds so sick,
we did a movie about Edgar's suicide
where we played ourselves.
Are you angry about something?
I'm angry about a lot of things, okay?
Okay.
It sounds so stupid and corny,
but I think by walking through it again,
it absolutely mended us.
Totally mended the relationship.
Don't ask, I have to go to another doctor
to figure that one out.
♪ [music] ♪
Thank you, thank you.
Have some fun.
Thank you. Thanks again.
I worship you, I worship you.
Get off your knees.
Oh Joan, I worship you.
Joan, Joan, Oh My God.
Joan Rivers everybody.
Please, can we clap?
[clapping]
Billy sent me this
for Opening Night.
Wait, wait.
Polly wants a fucking cracker.
Give Polly a fucking cracker now.
Old lady on the cover.[laughs]
Young people, young festival,
young ideas, old lady.
Hold on, get ready.
Hottest ticket, isn't that great?
And the front page.
[audience cheering and clapping]
The play went beyond
my wildest dreams in Edinburgh.
We had great reviews,
the audience adored it.
But who knows what's going to
happen in London.
It can turn on a dime.
[sirens]
Where are we?
Look! The signage is going up.
Look your canopy is going up.
Oh, isn't that sweet.
This is where we'll make the decision
to whether or not
I'm going to try to bring it to New York.
Oh, if the reviews are bad, we're dead.
We finished it and it was wonderful,
but it will not go to New York.
Joan this is__ Castelle,
for your lighting design.
I like a soft pink, I don't care
what it says.
Joan didn't want to open the play
in New York or LA
because even if it's great,
they will not give her the Kudos
that it's great because of who she is.
There is nothing she can do that will be
industry embraced.
How much does it hold?
Three nine three.
So it's 400.
Yeah, 400.
I'm never in the critics drawing.
I've always been considered a comic
and __ Comic or a Vegas Comic.
There is always an adjective
before my name
and it's never a nice adjective.
I go back to Fun City, which was
my first play in 1973
and they were very harsh to it.
It was a horrible experience and I will
not go through that again.
I moved us out of New York.
I said, "When that play closes,
we're out of here."
And we moved right after Fun City.
I just think
they are not going to like us.
And I didn't spend all this time
and all this energy to have this close
and it breaks my heart to see it die here.
Don't break--it won't die here.
That's the only thing that's killing me.
And I was thinking...
You're not going to lose it.
We won't let this go.
And I know it's your work--
your work of love.
I really think it's good.
I know.
Okay, onwards and upwards.
Hello press, be kind. Not too close.
Thank you. Hello.
Very nervous.
I don't want to go three nights.
I think you should celebrate
second nights,
when you're a success.
I think anyone
who celebrates opening nights
is a fool because you're not--
The opening night is your walk
to the execution.
So I will be very,very happy tomorrow
if all goes well and very smug.
And I will throw some diva scene
about something when I know
I have the power.
Right now,
I don't know if I have the power.
Is that enough glitter?
Yes, oh, God, yes.
Plenty.
Plenty of glitter.
Oh, shut that stupid bitch up.
[applause and shouting]
At the end of the show Johnny Carson,
on the air turned to me and said,
"You're going to be a star."
Vaginas drop, I did not know this.
I'm 75 years old and I tell you,
I haven't peaked.
And is why I'm going to go out that door,
the door after that,
and the door after that
and the door after that.
And I invite all of you, come with me.
Thank you.
[applause and clapping]
Whoa, okay.
That was pretty extraordinary.
All stood up, right at the end.
In America, if it goes out in America,
we love you, but you do stand up
all the time at the end of shows whether,
you know,
like you're supposed to or something.
Here they don't, except for this show.
It was a triumph.
Well, it's not a triumph until we read
in the papers.
I know.
[Sean] It would be nice if it's a triumph.
[female fan] We love you so much.
[male fan] Thank you very much.
Sorry to bother you.
[Joan] You're not bothering me, Joe.
I thought you were brilliant.
Are you feeling all the love
that we have here for you.
No. We'll feel it tomorrow
after the reviews.
Such a nice audience. Thank you.
Now let me ask you, when will we find out
about the reviews?
Tomorrow morning, first thing.
I'm pretty sure
they're gonna be fantastic.
Okay, what does it say?
Comedy, tragedy, surgery
and Rivers isn't going quietly.
Okay.
If the energy dips
slightly towards the end,
that is understandable
given the star's age.
They only gave me 3 stars out of 5.
Okay. Leicester Square,
all this play acting is an excuse
for a night of me, me, Joan.
She is not short on self-pity
and a passage about her relationship
with her daughter is pretty low
grade smultz, mind you.
It's--
You know--
- ...so wrong.
Exactly.
- It ends in a joke you ass.
Exactly, that's why,
he's just not getting, you know...
Longer exposure to her
even in a small theater betrays
a husky weakness of voice
that some may find monotonous.
What I'm thinking, Jo, is,
do I wanna take this to New York?
Do I want to sit in a taxi
in New York in 6 months,
and hear this and see this again?
Yeah.
I don't know, Jocelyn,
I don't know. I don't know.
I am not going to walk in to New York City
and be hurt the way Fun City hurt me.
My acting is my one
sacred thing in my life
and I will not have anyone
hurt me with that.
You can say I'm not a good comedian,
it does't bother me.
You say you didn't like me
as an actress, it's killing me.
And I don't want that in New York,
but I know I'm an actress.
It's all about acting, my career is an
actress' career. And I play a comedian.
So it's over, it's over.
No one will ever take me
seriously as an actress.
Don't be down-hearted.
Are you down-hearted?
I'm not down -- I'm just --
it's not what I thought
it was going to happen.
I thought what was going to happen was
I'm gonna sail in from Edinburgh,
everyone was going to love it
and then we were going
to pick our producer
and then move it forward and change it.
But not this like...
And of course there is no Billy around.
Billy is never around for trouble.
[Sean] Yeah.
This isn't trouble, but you know.
Any how.
♪ [music] ♪
The play is over and it hurts very much,
but I gotta take a deep breath
and start again.
♪ [music] ♪
[airplane roaring]
It wouldn't kill you
to get me another commercial.
Just remember when they come in
and ask for a man, I can be very butch.
So she'll do anything and really
get into it, like she loves it.
[male voice] Okay.
Okay, well, if there isn't anything else,
I'm very depressed.
[Billy] Bye.
[Jocelyn] Bye Steve.
[Steve] Okay, bye.
I don't want to retire,
I don't want to go and sit in the sun,
I don't want to learn and to garden.
I paint, who cares?
[beep, beep, beep]
[Billy] Hello, Emily Hope.
[Emily] Hi guys, a pleasure
to meet you both,
Explain to us what you're offering.
Yes, Platinum Rye
is hired by the ad agencies
to plug in celebrities to different
endorsement possibilities.
Yes?
[Emily] And they want to have
a meeting with Joan and talk about
where can we put her in.
I will do anything.
I will knock my teeth out
and do dentasure or whatever it is.
I mean, she's done--
I will wear a diaper, I don't give a shit.
[Larry Thompson] Joan has a fanaticism,
a maniacal focus to succeed.
And works at it every day.
I remember once meeting with
Richard Pryor. And I sat with him
and spent an hour with him
about his career, I said,
"Okay Richard what we're going to do is
we're going to do this,
we're going to do that,
and we're going to plan on this
and then in the next year,
we're going to do this
we're gonna do that
and he looked at me and he says,
"Larry that's all great,
but what the fuck do we do Monday?"
That's where Joan is.
"What the fuck do we do Monday?"
[Jocelyn] What is this?
That's my thing I've been reading.
I am holding dossiers of all the people
for the Celebrity Apprentice
that we pulled off of the Internet.
Rande, R-A-N-D-E.
Turn ons:
Taking in a good movie
while spending time with loved ones
and my beautiful puppy, Mercedes.
Aw.
Turn offs: Negative people
who are unkind
and have no respect for others.
Well, she's going to hate me.
Yeah, exactly.
I'm doing Celebrity Apprentice because
it's face time on NBC
and NBC has not let me be on NBC
since the Carson show.
I didn't want her to do it.
She didn't want to do it.
I thought it was F Class people,
but it is face time prime time network.
I think they'd be stupid to put me off
the first 4 shows,
so I maybe very free
the second half of October.
I think they are not going
to throw me off in the beginning
because I'm the only one
kind of that's a name.
Even though Donald says,
"These internationally known --
Entrepreneurs
...Entrepreneurs celebrities."
They had Paul Newman.
You know, Billy, I'm going to say that
in the Press Release,
that I was told Paul Newman was going to
be here.
I'm actually very excited
about Celebrity Apprentice
because Melissa, my daughter,
is going to be on the show with me,
which means we'll have a lot
of time to spend together.
Have you had your hair done yet?
No.
Jesus fucking Christ, Melissa, why?
- It's fine.
We've got 40 minutes,
that's more than enough.
That's more than enough, mom.
No, it's not.
For my hair, yes, it is.
All right, whatever.
Melissa red-eyed in
from LA this morning
and we started taping
Celebrity Apprentice tonight.
You've got to stop smoking immediately.
I went to a pulmonary guy today.
Am I boring you?
No, no, I'm listening.
I brought all my gum with me.
I'm down to like 2 for a day, that's it.
I'm telling you--
I know, but that's--you know,
be supporive that I'm down to that.
He said women react differently
to cigarettes than men.
I'm saying I'm down to like 2 or 3 a day.
He said, more woman are dying
of lung cancer than breast cancer.
And nobody's discussing that.
So that's very interesting.
Well, I'm down to like, 2 to 3 a day.
So--
Yeah, I'm just telling--
What you're saying, I know.
...you're really loading the gun.
- No, I know. I know.
But I'm just saying at least be supportive
that I've got it down to that.
You scare the bejesus out of me.
Great pressure is, what if
she gets voted off ahead of me?
It's going to be very traumatic.
I would rather I get voted off
ahead of her.
I know, that I will always hold back,
I know that and so--
'cause I don't want ever
to come out brighter than Melissa
and smarter than Melissa.
I just don't want--
I don't compete with her in that level.
I believe that consciously
she would believe that
and then even if I did win
she'd say she held back,
but I don't think she really could.
Okay, see ya later.
[Driver] See you in a bit.
[Melissa Rivers] In the business,
you have to put yourself first.
You gotta protect yourself.
And my mother will tell you that
she only wants me to win
and then she'll do something without even
realizing it that it's very destructive.
And I think it's a very tough dynamic,
because I truly think
it's completely subconscious with her.
I've got something here,
you open that.
It's a nice Doonie & Bourke bag.
It's a very nice goodie bag.
Yes.
I feel very out of place,
I'm the oldest by far.
They all were all talking and chatting
and for a long time I stood by myself.
I feel very isolated.
Well, I see you also bring a lot of that
on yourself.
I think you don't make any--
Like tonight, you made no effort
to be like welcoming.
I stood there.
Well, no, I'm saying
you were on your Blackberry so fast,
and I tried to introduce you to people
and you were already like, "Oh, hi,"
because you get so shy and that's
what people don't know about you.
Hell, I wouldn't walk over to you.
Well, they didn't.
But you set it up for that,
you don't realize
that you do that kinda--
All stand ups are innately insecure.
Who would stand
on a stage by themselves
and say laugh,
laugh at me, laugh with me
I don't care just laugh.
And I think that's just sort of
the nature of the beast
Overall, it just drove my perception
growing up in the world of comedians,
they are all very damaged,
and they need that reassurance,
it's all a cover.
♪ [music] ♪
It's been a blood bath.
They don't play fair, they cheat.
So Melissa is fired on Tuesday
and I know Joan was very upset.
She is a snake.
Annie Duke was on the team with Melissa
and absolutely conspired
to get Melissa fired.
Annie Douch, that fucking moron.
Would you, right now, grab onto my blog.
Yup.
And onto my Twitter, it should be,
"Anne Douche, that moron,
she should kiss my ass."
She should kiss my Jewish ass.
But not with those non-kosher lips.
Not with those big lips--that's it.
She should kiss my Jewish ass,
but not with those big pig lips.
You think that's too rough?
So tell me, you didn't think
it was going to get vicious?
No, I just thought it was
at least going to be moderately fair.
And my concern is how I will be portrayed.
because I have more of an
image issue than you do.
So that's a little unsettling.
It meant you're gonna to look
very angry, they already said,
when you left you,
really called them all kinds of names.
Um-hm.
So that's there.
But you all--
But if they cut it to show
that I was telling the truth.
Oh, they are not going to cut it
to show that you were telling the truth
'cause they don't care,
they are gonna show that you left...
[Melissa] Pissed off.
...pissed off.
But you also came back
and you also worked
and you also just--that's all right.
But I'm just saying--
I think it makes you more interesting,
Melissa, frankly.
They're gonna go on saying...
You have done really an amazing job
but Melissa, you're fired.
Whore, pit viper.
I want my [beep],
I want it now.
I'm not leaving without it.
It makes me very upset
to see her that hurt.
It wasn't even her--
it was the frustration of the lies.
It is such a cruel business.
Sometimes, I just want to say to her,
"Why in God's name are you
opening yourself up to such punishment?"
Mine is not a choice.
Mine is, ah--I always say it's like--
people always say,
"Why are you in the business?"
Ask a nun why she's a nun.
That's my drive, at 4:00 in the morning
in the airport.
It's I have no choice.
And that's where I was
from the time I could figure it out.
No question where I was going.
There were not drugs, there was no sex,
there was no nothing,
nothing 'til I got my job.
That's where I was going.
And just go away.
[siren wailing]
♪ [music] ♪
We're having--it's going to be
a long evening.
We're doing two shows tonight.
Joan Rivers?
- Yes?
Do you mind autographing these for me?
- Oh, my goodness yes, of course.
I love you.
Every Wednesday night when I'm
in New York,
I work at some tiny little club
where I can practice my act.
I just talk about anything
and everything that annoys me.
Thank you.
[male fan] You don't get the recognition
you deserve.
Damn right, William.
Okay, see?
I have a fan. I have William.
The minute your not angry about things.
The minute you're not upset about things.
What are you talking about?
Oh, my grandson was so cute--
Pfft! It's not my comedy.
I'm furious about everything.
Furious about everything.
Good things don't always happen
to good people
and I'm very angry about it.
But I didn't have the anger
to be a comedian.
Anger fuels the comedy.
[audience laughing]
I hate everybody.
I hate old people.
I hate ugly children.
I hate fat people.
I hated China.
I hate whiners.
Oh, I hate dead people.
I even have the three wise men
who I hate.
I love anal sex because you can
do other things, you know,
it's like, you can iron,
you can read a book.
[audience laughing]
Get your e-mails on your Blackberry.
[applause]
♪ [music] ♪
Well, right now, we're getting
this 17 foot table up the stairs.
These two guys just walked it up
seven flights and...
Just bring it right here.
Today is Thanksgiving,
favorite time of the year.
Favorite time of the year.
Lucy and Cooper
come up of course.
And then I invite my friends,
and many of them are strays,
are single woman
or my neighbors from downstairs.
It's sad.
[Jocelyn] Why is that?
I don't know, just sad that it seems
you have fewer friends in New York.
And I know when something
wonderful happens
there maybe three people I call,
when maybe, 15 years ago,
there would have been six people I call.
So many people are dying, my God.
They'd better eat fast tonight.
[laughing]
Oh, it's cold.
Every Thanksgiving, I bring meals
from God's Love We Deliver,
to people who absolutely are
too ill to go out.
This year, I asked my grandson,
Cooper to come with me.
If you what?
If we can stop at an electronic store...
Yes, Ma'am.
- ...his PSP is broken.
But if you're very good,
I'll buy you a new one for your birthday.
Well, my friend had three of them
and he gave me one.
That's very nice.
Is this the one he gave you?
Yes.
He had three of them?
Has he got a single grandfather?
[Joan laughing]
Flip your hands.
You have great hands Cooper..
And God's Love we deliver,
when I started out
and I'm the board,
we used to give
AIDS patients that were going,
we would give them food.
Well, now AIDS is chronic
and I'm still delivering the fucking food,
I'm so pissed, I am so--
Oh, do you know what it's like?
Thanksgiving morning, ding dong,
the guys opens the door, "You again?"
[audience laughing]
"This is the 3rd fucking
Thanksgiving in a row, buddy."
"Ms. Rivers, just leave it over there.
I'm on my way to the gym."
The gym?
[audience laughing]
You're going to die today,
AIDS or me, I'm not sure which.
[audience laughing]
Oh look, she's got--awww, how nice--
do you wanna ring?
Hello, hello.
- [female voice] Hi.
I'm Joan Rivers, this is my grandson,
Cooper...
Oh, wow. Nice to see you.
Joan Rivers, "The Joan Rivers?"
- I pay the bills.
You have entertained me for years,
Miss Rivers.
I'm so glad.
I'm a photographer.
And you can see there's something
going on here. That's wonderful.
Right there, I photographed
the same drugstore for 20 years.
Every time they change the
price of cigarettes.
Oh, how brilliant is that?
- Thank you.
Where was it shown?
- Life Magazine.
I have taken
over a hundred thousand photos,
so you might even know my work.
Look up flofox.com.
[Flo] Thank you.
- [Jocelyn] Happy Thanksgiving Dinner.
I can't wait to get out of here
and get home and look you up.
Flo Fox, baby.
My name is Flo Fox.
[TV Host] ... Flo Fox right now.
What happened that caused your
eyesight to start to fail?
I believe it's connected
with multiple sclerosis.
I walk with a cane,
I'm a little off-balanced.
First my eyes went,
and ah...
Oh, so sad.
There's a sexy, young, artistic, edgy,
New York tough Bohemian girl.
It's amazing isn't it?
Life is so mean.
[people talking]
[ting, ting, ting]
Thank you all for being here.
This morning,
I delivered meals with my grandson,
for God's Love We Deliver,
and may I tell you, we are so blessed,
we are so blessed.
I thank God every minute
that I ever step into a limousine,
I know it sounds silly.
Since 1968, they have been
sending limousines for me.
And I never get into one that I don't say,
"Thank you God. I am so chosen."
And I thank you all for being here
and I thank God
for another wonderful Thanksgiving.
[female voice] Here, here.
[applause]
[people talking]
♪ [music] ♪
We're at the Kennedy Center
in Washington D.C.
I am here to do
a tribute to George Carlin.
I find this whole thing
very hypocritical.
This is everything that George
claimed he wasn't.
George hated the establishment.
George hated the people
that are going to be there tonight,
which is going to be a bunch of older,
very wealthy Republications.
All the things that George fought against
tonight will all be together
because he's getting the Mark Twain Award.
It's like me getting a big award
from the German Bund.
[laughs]
And now for funniest Jewish
not in the ovens, John Rosenberg.
[laughs]
But there is an importance to me
for this type of event for comedy
because I'm always left out of it.
So for me this is nice to be included,
because I'm usually not included.
Once a Jew, always a Jew.
[laughing]
I'm going in to clean that bathroom.
[male voice] Have you seen that shower
there? It's kind of interesting.
Oh, look.
The writers are ready for you
when you want.
I'm ready for the writers.
- [male voice] Okay.
Okay, where are the writers?
They're coming in here?
[male voice] Yeah.
Is it just the two of us?
- Yeah! Three of us.
Miss Rivers, the, "Fuck," thing,
I know the executive producers
are a little concerned about that.
Yes. And well they should be.
I will probably have one,
"Fuck," somewhere
That's fine.
Just because the organization--
- No exactly, one is fine
and it will be "bleeped" for TV.
- Yes.
Thank you.
[male voice] All right, See ya later.
Thanks Joan. See you in a bit.
All of them are is so much
funnier than I am.
See, when you see the line up--
And you know that John Stewart
as 12 writers work on this.
And you know Gary
had 6 writers work on this.
And you know all these people,
look who's here,
they all have professional staffs.
♪ [music] ♪
[people talking]
[male reporter] Joan, what does it
feel like to be a comedic icon?
I'm sure there are comedians
that come up to you
and say you were an inspiration.
I'm not ready to be an "Icon."
I'm not ready to be told, "Thank you."
Fuck you.
[laughing]
[voice on TV]
Don't know him.
[TV announcer] Dennis Leary.
- Clever.
[TV announcer] Bill Maher.
- Brilliant.
[TV announcer] Joan Rivers.
- Okay.
[TV announcer] Gary Shandling.
- Brilliant.
[TV announcer] John Stewart.
- Smart.
[TV announcer] Ben Stiller.
- Lucky.
[TV announcer] And Lily Tomlin.
- Brilliant.
[TV announcer] Ladies and Gentlemen,
George Carlin.
[male laughing]
[audience clapping and cheering]
Billy Jack's great---lounge.
All my favorite ---,
I think I'm being caught.
[female announcer] Smothers Brothers
and Laugh-In and it was just a great time
[Richard Belzer] Few people
are always funny,
but certainly one of the chosen people
is our next presenter,
the fabulous, Joan Rivers,
ladies and gentlemen.
[applause]
We used to play these terrible clubs,
literally where you didn't get paid,
you passed the hat.
And some nights the hat would come back
with a severed head.
Some nights...
[audience laughing]
And they asked me to say
a couple words about George
and I kept thinking that is so unfair,
you cannot sum
George Carlin up in 2 words.
Give me at least 7.
[audience laughing]
And...
[Bille Maher] You were so funny.
I think today went very well.
I think I did not embarrass myself at all.
I think I was fine.
I think I was funny in a lot of people,
Not as funny as a lot of people,
but, yeah, I was perfectly fine.
♪ [music] ♪
I am getting ready to go to Wisconsin.
I've never done an act before in mukluks.
[laughter]
- I have no idea.
They're scared of me.
When I say, "Where are the gays?"
They are going to tell us dead,
we killed them.
[laughter]
Why am going to Wisconsin?
That thing called money.
They are so desperate to get me,
they are paying me.
That's why I'm going to Wisconsin.
I worked last night.
I work in Tortonto until,
like, 2:30 in the morning,
on the shopping channel.
And I got up at 5 o'clock
to make a 7 o'clock plane or something
to Chicago.
And then from Chicago, I took a little,
what they call puddle jumper,
it was adorable.
How is the gay community here?
That I really don't know.
- Oh see, ask your cousin.
[laughing]
- Ask you wife's brother.
- [female voice] Is this the remote place?
Oh, no.
[female voice] Where is the most
remote place you've ever played?
The most remote place I've ever played
is Reykjavik, Iceland.
I played on --
- Juneau...
Oh, are they wrong,
that was called the Texas Motel.
They are so off.
[laughing]
Some places, as you know,
are better than others.
Ah, this will not be
my first choice of decor.
The audience are gonna be very born again,
I have a feeling.
Very fundamentalist and they are going
to get very shaken up.
Get the check.
Whatever I do on stage-- are they
gonna clean the stage a little bit?
because I kind of
roll around on that stuff.
So a little--yuck, it's gum.
Aren't you the makeup person?
You'll win the award,
At showing up with no makeup.
Don't you have your make-up?
Aren't you the makeup girl?
She's the makeup girl,
you should be wearing makeup.
May...Good month.
[male voice] Next year.
- May of next year.
You leave New York, you leave LA,
you all leave the world.
But that's what makes it charming.
♪ [music] ♪
[cheering and applause]
Where are we? What the hell is going on?
I was out in the casino. The guy put
a quarter in and fish came out.
[audience laughing]
Never mind Viagra, what about Cialis?
36 fucking hours a man has an erection.
An 85-year-old man for 36 hours.
That's devil's work.
And on this poor old dried out old wives
and these guys on top of them,
in and out, in and out, in and out.
They're going to set them on fire.
[audience laughing]
- Yes.
I hate children. The only child
I think I would have liked ever
was Helen Keller 'cause didn't talk.
And it's just--
[male audience] That's not very funny.
Yes it is. And if you don't, then leave.
[male audience] It ain't funny
if you have a deaf son.
I happen to have a deaf mother.
Oh, you stupid ass.
Let me tell you what comedy is about--
[male audience] You go ahead
and tell me.
Oh, please. You are so stupid.
Comedy is to make everybody laugh
at everything and deal with things.
You idiot.
My mother is deaf,
you stupid son of a bitch. Don't tell me.
And just in case you're going to hear me
in the hallway
I lived for 9 years with a man
with one leg, okay, you asshole?
And we're going to talk about
what it's like to have a man with one leg.
who lost it in World War II
and then went back to get it
'cause that's fucking littering.
[audience laughing and clapping]
So don't you tell me...what's funny.
Comedy is to make us laugh.
9-11, if we didn't laugh
where the hell would we all be.
Think about that.
[audience clapping]
Where the hell would be all be.
How can you not find Osama?
There is one outlet, he's on dialysis,
there was one outlet
in all of Afghanistan.
Find the plug. And follow the cord.
[audience laughing and clapping]
♪ [music] ♪
Okay. How about that?
"I have a deaf son!"
Ah, what a good way to build!
That was a very difficult moment.
It throws you terribly.
Because you know,
the audience is so nervous
and so scared to laugh.
Your mind is going a mile a minute,
"Where am I going to go?"
"What am I gonna do?"
"Where am I gonna take them?"
So there are two things going on,
your mouth and your head.
Luckily, I was able to get them back.
[female fan] You are so--
I never laughed so hard in my life.
You are a good laugher
and that makes such a different.
Oh, I know.
And that rotten guy. I was ready
to get up and tell him to leave.
He has a deaf son.
I know, but he's got to realize
this is comedy.
Comedy.
I felt terribly sorry
for the man with the deaf son.
And of course, he's angry.
Of course he's angry and I get that.
But don't ruin the whole act.
Maybe it got it out of him
and maybe it's good
what happened to him too.
He had a kind of a catharsis.
And you're driving us?
- Yup.
Have you been drinking?
- No, Ma'am.
Have you been drugging?
- No.
Have you been whoring?
- I never did.
Okay, well, that's good,
you'll be relaxed.
Just head for New York
and just get me home.
There is nothing like your own bed.
Nothing like your own bed.
They called my agent.
They wanted to get William Shatner.
He said, "No, they wanted to get
George Hamilton",
He said, "No."
So I said, "A woman should do it.
I'll do it."
Extend. Extend, which is you take a pill
and the man's penis just grows...grows.
Not penile enlargement. Just like, mmm,
"Oh look who's a big boy now."
[Jocelyn] Joan will turn nothing down,
at all, nothing.
[Larry] And she hears the clock ticking
every minute of every hour of every day.
We're going to Palm Springs for--
what is this for?
Do you know what this is for?
The Betty Ford Clinic.
It's for the Betty Ford Clinic,
so they will be very serious about drugs.
[laughing]
Alright. Are they lining you up
like Nazis? Alright, that's alright.
"Sorry bitch, I'm not Carol Channing,
but this will have to do.
Much love, Joan Rivers."
Thank you.
So I have S's. "Ssss..., Ssss..."
Even a little more.
If you take out the top or the bottom
that usually works pretty well.
This is the early Joan. This is me.
Oh, does this tampon make me look fat?
We're gonna go straight down this hallway.
I'll follow you.
- Okay.
Love that your nails match your dress.
It's so fabulous.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Be careful, I have a friend.
Victoria Beckham, yuck, yuck.
"Does the tampon make me look fat?"
I can't stand...
Okay, up we go.
We're going to Minneapolis, huh?
It's cold there.
Alright. And thank you.
You were terrific.
[male voice] Pleasure meeting you.
- [Joan]Thank you.
Hello.
I don't care if it's God himself.
No one is to call my room until 6:30.
[Hotel clerk] Okay.
Save your money while you're younger,
that you don't hold yourself out
when you're old.
To the Roast Comedy Central.
Oh, God.
- I know, but the money is extraordinary.
I'm so depressed,
I can't even go there with you then.
This is the cherry on the cake.
Mohammad, can you stop for a moment,
so I can get out in front of the car.
[laughing]
Can you just run me over.
End it now, Mohammad.
Do you know the jokes. Every joke
is gonna be plastic surgery or old.
It comes back at you doesn't it.
- Yep.
God...
Ms. Rivers to the set, please.
[bell rings]
[male voice] Action.
This tastes like urine.
You crazy fucking bitch.
The crew loves me.
They keep telling you it's an honor.
I'm telling you
that if I had invested wisely,
I wouldn't be doing this.
By the way, did you know
that I've never done a roast in my life.
They are so disgusting.
They are not disgusting.
It is an honor, I'm telling you.
Now don't make that face.
- But the money is very good.
The money is good, which is an honor.
I mean I'm an artist,
and I'm doing it for the art like you are.
Yes.
A couple of artist with easels,
sitting around, collecting our money.
[male voice] Joan will cross to her seat.
Alright. Let's say 3-2-1 go.
Talk about lucky.
Brad and Angelina is having sale.
Look at them.
Go on down now.
Auntie Joanie is busy.
Fuck shh..
Okay. No, no, no.
Don't go yet. We're just--
and this is at this point,
that's when you would go --
Could somebody help me here, please.
No, no, no.
Don't bother.
[male voice] You know everybody
is giving you a standing ovation,
that joke probably won't read
that long.
I beg you, it will read. I will wait
until the stand ovation is over.
I will get up here--
[male voice] They will not sit down
until you sit down.
Well then, they are going to stand
until I sit down. I'm pleading with you,
don't knock every joke
or it's not going to be funny.
I'm begging you.
I'm pleading with you.
I will thank them
and I will either sit down
and miss the chair.
I will do something funny.
Because I am a funny person.
[crew laughing and clapping]
Hello, hello, hello.
We are here to celebrate the career
of a ground breaking comedian
and a legendary bitch.
[audience laughing and clapping]
How much worse
could your real face look than that
clown mask you've had welded
on your head.
Look at her, she's a cougar.
Freddy Cougar.
Joan's face has been lifted so many times,
that when she sneezes,
she has to blow her clit.
[audience laughing and clapping]
I get mad at myself.
I think at this age,
you've been doing it since 1966,
and you shouldn't let them
upset you anymore, but they do.
I did the Comedy Central Roast, okay.
Which was great, which was great.
I was--they said
such mean disgusting filthy--
they called me a whore and a cunt
and a this or a that.
I kept thinking, how do they know me?
It's just --
[audience laughing]
Oh, sure, turn against the Queen.
Said Marie Antoinette.
Yeah! Nothing you're going to do better
with Kathy Griffin, fuck you!
And it's just--
[audience laughing]
If she lasts 45 years, then go stand--
Just kidding.
I love Kathy Griffin.
♪ [music] ♪
[Melissa] Where's Billy these days?
I have no idea.
He's no longer part of my career.
He can't be.
You spend too much energy
looking for Billy
and too many phone calls coming in
from people that haven't heard from Billy.
And I can't deal with it.
[Melissa] You know it's bad
when people say something to me.
No, literally, I run into people
and they're like,
"Oh, we were trying to reach Billy
and he never called us back."
Yeah, let us know.
Just say, "Call Jocelyn."
Billy, unfortunately,
is no longer part of my team.
I sent him an e-mail saying
"We are no longer in business together."
He just can't be counted on
and it's killing me.
I'll tell you why it really upset me.
Billy is one of the last links
that I can say, "Do you remember?"
And I have to cut that off.
And I think that it's not the business,
that's where I cannot tell you
I will never not miss Billy.
He was there when Melissa was born.
He was there for Edgar's funeral.
You know, he's a link
I have no one to say,
"Do you remember when
Bernie Brillstein gave this party
and Edgar was the only one
that came in black tie."
I know that he's--
he was my last memory bank.
And I had no one,
no one to say that to now,
and that is very difficult for me.
Tonight is a live finale of
Celebrity Apprentice.
And it is between me and Annie Duke.
If I win, I'm back.
I'm back in spite of being a woman.
and in spite of being 75,
and in spite of being black balled by NBC.
I'm back you bastards.
You know, it's been a tremendous,
tremendous season.
Annie, do you know
what I'm going to say?
No, I have no idea.
I'm going to say Annie, you're fired.
[cheering and applause]
♪ [music] ♪
It's great.
[background conversations]
It's great. It's terrific.
Here we go,
but it's just Celebrity Apprentice,
it's not the Academy Awards
but it was wonderful
and I'm very happy I won.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
[Larry] I've always said,
"You can't get hit by lightning
if you're not standing out in the rain."
Nobody can stand in the rain
longer than Joan Rivers.
She will stay there,
she's the last person standing.
She'll let it rain, she'll let it rain,
she'll let it rain
because she knows lightning can hit
because it's hit her more than once.
But she knows
you have to stay out in the rain.
And she did.
Line 2, okay.
How long, my sweetheart?
Yeah, so tell me. Tell me yes or no.
Just tell me fair.
Yeah.
Alright, so tell me.
Tell me, yes or no?
Just tell me a bit.
[screams]
That's fabulous. Are you kidding?
Jocelyn! We were picked up.
No way, awesome!
- We got it, all right.
You know what the real pinnacle is
in a comedy career is?
It's not an Oscar.
It's not one thing,
it's the fact that you are still doing it.
That's really what's
so rockstar about her.
She's really the master
of sticking in there.
[Jocelyn] Let's talk about
what this is going to entail.
It's a photo shoot for
the New York Times.
I could do it Monday afternoon,
if they want. I'm still in town.
Right now,
everything is absolutely wonderful.
I'm the golden girl.
But I have been here before
and I know nothing is yours permanently.
And you better enjoy it
while it's happening.
So next week,
Monday, Regis and Kelly,
book signing at QVC.
Tuesday, WOR, Rachel Ray,
Howard Stern, Cutting Room.
Wednesday, Florida, breakfast lecture,
do an afternoon book signing,
back to Miami, perform 2 shows.
Thursday, LA, The Doctors,
Radio Show,
red eying home, QVC,
corporate booking,
then back to The Cutting Room.
Get him out of the picture.
[laughter]
It's me alone.
Isn't artist--.
Wherever you have it, thank you.
I am opening for Don Rickles.
And when they say "Opening"
what it is he and I split the money
and years ago when we started
I said, "I'll open,"
because I get out earlier.
And he's still pissed about it.
[laughing]
Theater is wonderful here.
It's a Vegas-sized thereafter.
It's 1800 or 2000.
[female voice] No, it's 4000, yeah.
It's a 4000-person theatre.
I'm nervous.
[laughing]
I go way back with Joan.
When she was in Vegas
and she was a struggling comedian.
We got to know each other.
She's done an outstanding job
with her career. I mean that.
She has outstanding timing,
and she takes hee work very seriously.
And if I didn't marry my Barbara,
I would have married Joan.
and with that remark--
ah, ah...
Oh God, I was kidding around.
Aw, God.
Don Rickles is in his late 80's
and he is still hilarious.
He's like George Burns
who was amazing
until he was in his late 90's.
And Phyllis Diller, until she was 92,
she was just laid it down.
And I'd like to beat them all.
And I think I will.
And since it's so sick, I think I will.
First wife is always some poor
dumb bitch who he married on the way up.
Second wife is always like--
and he's an asshole and he marries her.
And the third wife, he's 96,
his balls are on the ground
and she's 11 and she's Chinese.
I love you.
[audience laughing]
Thank you. I'll see you later.
♪ [band playing] ♪
This is where I belong.
The only time I'm truly, truly happy
is when I'm on a stage.
I -- a good job once.
It's embarrasing.
I keep saying she's wonderful
and you always fail me.
I am a performer, that is my life.
That is what I am. That's it.
♪ [music] ♪
I do hate children
and that's the truth.
Oh God, at Halloween,
and they--
"Oh, lady, we don't like apples,"
then just eat the razor blades.
It's so--
Joan Rivers, I love you,
love you, love you.
I love you, love you back.
And who is it to?
- Lucy.
I can't spell it.
- ...jewelry. Love you!
I love everything
that you've done for woman.
Love all your humor,
all your breaks.
Oh, thank you.
- You're the best.
Oh, Lucy...
- Love you.
Lucy, I love you back.
Surprise.
I'm so bored, that they have
taken torture away in the United States.
Oh, it was--
Oh, like, like--
Oh, like torture was bad.
Oh, wooly-bully, wooly-bully,
Oh, big fucking deal,
try getting a bikini wax one time.
Get a Brazilian wax,
you'll give up secrets
like you never knew you had.
[audience laughing and clapping]
[shouting]
They are doing a documentary
of my life.
And you said earlier, they are
just waiting for the moment, right?
They are praying that I die
doing this film.
Wouldn't that be great?
Wouldn't that be amazing?
They got the last view of Joan Rivers.
It would give them such a hook.
People would watch.
- People would watch.
That's sick.
- We were-- but it wouldn't--
but still, -- very commercial.
You'd watch.
- I'd watch.
[laughing]
Wouldn't you?
[END]